Jan Rodson M. Burgos

Web Developer

Kabankalan City, Negros Occidental

janrburgos@gmail.com

github.com/janrburgos (7)



Summary

I'm a former Marine Engineer with over 5 years of experience working onboard international vessels. I shifted to a web development / programming career because I want to grow and succeed in a career in which I am passionate about while at the same time creating something that would make people's lives easier. I believe that I have skills which I acquired from my previous experience as an engineer which I can bring into my next profession as a programmer / developer.

Key Skills

- Quick Learning Critical Thinking Troubleshooting Problem Solving Adaptability
 - Resourcefulness Attention to Detail Team Player Integrity •

Experience

2015-04 – 2020-12 Officer-In-Charge – Engineering Watch

BW Shipping Philippines, Inc.

- In charge of maintenance, overhauling, repairing, and carrying out tests of marine equipment and machineries in order to keep them efficiently running at +99%.
- Preparing requisition orders of needed spare parts of machineries while also ensuring that costs are economically sound.
- Supervise and train other crewmembers (20+ crewmembers per contract/year) during routine duties and emergency drills about topics related to safety, technical work related to the job and et cetera.

2012-06 – 2013-05 **Engine Cadet**

Southfield Agencies, Inc.

Had my internship onboard an international vessel as an Engine Cadet during my 3rd year in college.

Education

2021-02 – Present Full Stack Web Development Course

Uplift Code Camp

- Coding bootcamp focusing on the MERN Stack.
- My projects made from this bootcamp can be found in my web portfolio <u>janrburgos.github.io/portfolio</u>

2010-06 – 2014-03 **Bachelor of Science in Marine Engineering**

John B. Lacson Colleges Foundation - Bacolod

 A Scholar of Norwegian Shipowners Association Cadetship Program and Dean's Lister.